

New Delhi, India

□ abhishekvasudev7@gmail.com

9582044450http://abhishekvasudev.github.io

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abhishek-vasudev https://github.com/abhishekvasudev/ https://www.facebook.com/abhishek.vasudev.7 https://www.codechef.com/users/abhishekv

About Me

I'm an undergraduate student who's passion is coding and software development. I love to do competitive programming. I have hands on experience in software development and team leadership.

My work during internship has been acknowledged by the respective employer. I am a team player If you have a role I fit in, please get in touch.

Work Experience

Intern: Web Developer | June 2017 - September 2017

Comezo Infotech Pvt. Ltd.

Worked as frontend developer.

Languages used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, MySQL, PHP Projects: Developed the company website and 3 more projects

Company website: http://comezo.in/

Responsible for developing efficient and mobile responsive website.

Responsible for developing efficient and mobile responsive web
Developed dynamic JavaScript and JQuery codes.
Responsible for Search Engine Optimization for the website.
Developed front end of report for school result.
Developed website for company's client Preducate.
Redesigned front of company's product LMS.
Analysed data of school result and formulated MySQL queries.
Got introduced with moodle and worked on it.

Freelance Web Developer | October 2017 - January 2018

Worked as Freelance Front end Developer.
Developed the company website: http://pararthya.com/
Languages used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap

Worked on SEO for the website.

Integrated email service
 Optimized image size for fast load of website
 Developed dynamic JavaScript code for website

Projects

Hand Written Digits Recognition System - (January 2018)

A machine learning application which recognizes and correctly identify hand written digits. It scans the image of digits and converts them into data.

Technology used: Python, Tensor Flow, MNIST data set My Role: Individual project.

Facial Detection System - (January 2018)

A Facial Detection system is a computer application capable of identifying a person from a digital image or a video frame from a video source.

Technology used: C++, OpenCV

My Role: Individual project.
Future Task: Develop Facial Recognition System

Park Assist - (August 2017 - November 2017)

A mobile application used to help a user by showing nearby parking spaces under the radius of $1\,\mathrm{km}$. The application either takes the current position or the user given address as the search point. The application also provides parking management to the parking owners. The available spaces and booking of a space happen in real time. This is achieved with the use of Firebase.

Technology used: React Native, CSS, JSON, Firebase, draw.io
My Role: Both Front-end and back-end, prepared PowerPoint Presentation
Future Task: Develop Vendor Dashboard

Teacher Assesssment - (February 2017 - Present)

It is a software tool for evaluating teacher performance based on student feedback.Students will get opportunity to grade their teachers so that university can bring improvements in teaching process of faculty. The software evaluates the performance of teacher based on the inputs provided by the students. This will help the new students to know about the teaching faculty and the university to bring improvements in the faculty.

Technology used: Java core, JavaFX, MySQL, CSS My Role: Front-end, Back-end Future Task: Implement it at my college

Quiz - (December 2016 - June 2018)

A standalone application for conducting multiple choice based quiz or tests where a user can make test and students can give test.

Technology Used: Java Core, Java Swing My Role: Front-end, Back-end Future Task: Implement it at my college

Sudoku Game - (September 2016)

A simple application of Sudoku gam

Technology Used: Java Core, Java Swing My Role: Front-end, Back-end

Achievements

Shortlisted for screening process for the role of Software Developer at Google

Scured Gold and Silver Medal at National Cyber Olympiad in 2012 and 2013 respectively.

Skills

Java Core

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

MySQL & Firebase

React Native

PHP & Adobe Photoshop

Relevent Course Work

Object Oriented Programming

Java Programming

Algorithm Design and Analysis

Machine Learning

Software Engineering

Advanced Cryptography and Network Security Database Management System

Advanced Computer Network

Education

B.Tech | Information Technology

2014 - 2018

Aggregate: 82.75%

Senior Secondary(XII)

BVB Mehta Vidyalaya

2013 - 2014 Aggregate: 81.40%

BVB Mehta Vidvalava

2011 - 2012

Aggregate: 9.2 CGPA (87.40%)

Positions of Responsibility

Team Leader, Smart India Hackathon 2017

Led Team SPI, consisting of 6 members, shortlisted for grand finale

Vice President, Special Projects Initiative(SPI)

Core team member of Special Projects Initiative(SPI) of IT Department of college.

Conducted inter section IT department Hackathon

President, Techedge Club

Elected as President of Techedge Club, Computer Society, at Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan's Meht.

Vidyalaya. Conducted Dewang Mehta Memorial Inter School IT Competition.

Event Organizer, Innoviz 2016

Organized 2 events at the annual techno-cultural fest, Innoviz 2016, at college.